Department of Archaeology fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Course outlines and examinations, 1966 - 1986; F-4-8; 1.04 m of textual records
  - ARC 871, 872, 876 Special / Selected Topics in Archaeology, 1980 - 1981; F-4-8-0-0-81 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 881-5 North American Prehistory; ARC 895-5 Special Topics in Archaeology, 1980 - 1981; F-4-8-0-0-82 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 101-3 Pre-historic Past, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-83 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 131-3 Human Origins, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-84 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 223-3 The Prehistory of Canada (Centennial Museum), 1982; F-4-8-0-0-85 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 272-3 Archaeology of the Old World, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-86 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 273-3 Archaeology of the New World, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-87 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 301-2 Prehistoric and Primitive Art, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-88 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 330-5 Prehistory of Latin America, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-89 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 332-3 Special Topics and Fact and Fantasy in Archaeology, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-90 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 333-3 Special Topics in Archaeology, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-91 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 334-3 Near East Prehistory, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-92 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 335-5 Special Topics Using Computers and Statistics in Archaeology, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-93 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 336-5 Special Topics in Prehistoric and Primitive Art, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-94 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 340-3 Introductory Zooarchaeology, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-95 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 360-3 Indian Cultures of North America, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-96 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 365-3 Ecological Archaeology, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-97 (Archival box - standard 4-25)
  - ARC 370-3 Western Pacific Prehistory, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-98 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 371-5 Archaeology Theory, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-99 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 372-5 Archaeology Laboratory Techniques, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-100 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 373-5 Human Osteology, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-101 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 374-3 Prehistory of South and East Asia, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-102 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 376-5 Quantitative methods in Archaeology, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-103 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 385-3 Fossil Man, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-104 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 411-5 Archaeological Dating, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-105 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 432-5 Advanced Physical Anthropology, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-106 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 433, 434, 435, 436 Field School, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-107 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 438-3 Geoarchaeology, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-108 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 439-3 Early Man and Environments, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-109 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 440 Advanced Zooarchaeology, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-110 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 442-5 Forensic Anthropology, 1982; F-4-8-0-0-111 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 473-3 Regional Studies in Archaeology: Africa, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-112 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 476-5 Regional Studies in Archaeology: Northwest Pacific, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-113 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 480-5 Directed Readings, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-114 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 485-5 Lithic Technology - Hayden, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-115 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 871-5 Selected Topics in Archaeological Theory - Shutler, Hayden, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-116 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 876-5 Special Topics in Archaeological Method - Nance, 1983; F-4-8-0-0-117 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 895-5 Special Topics - Driver, Skinner, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-118 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 896-5 Directed Readings - Driver, Shutler, 1982 - 1983; F-4-8-0-0-119 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC Graduate Comprehensive Examinations, 1983 - 1984; F-4-8-0-0-120 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 101-3 Prehistoric Past, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-121 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 131-3 Human Origins, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-122 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 200-3 Special Topics in World History, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-123 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 201-3 Fact and Fantasy, 1985; F-4-8-0-0-124 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 223-3 The Prehistory of Canada, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-125 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 272-3 Archaeology of the Old World, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-126 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 273-3 Archaeology of the New World, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-127 (Archival box - standard 4-26)
  - ARC 301-2 Prehistoric and Primitive Art: Oceania, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-128 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 330-5 Prehistory of Latin America, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-129 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 332-3 Special Topics in Archaeology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-130 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 333-3 Special Topics in Archaeology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-131 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 334-3 Special Topics in Archaeology, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-132 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 335-3 Special Topics: Stats and Computers; Seminar (Paleo-Indians), 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-133 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 336-3 Prehistoric and Primitive Art-Northwest Coast Indian Art, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-134 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 340-5 Introduction to Zooarchaeology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-135 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 360-3 Indian Cultures of North America, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-136 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 365-3 Ecological Archaeology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-137 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 371-5 Archaeological Theory, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-138 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 372-5 Archaeology Laboratory Techniques, 1985; F-4-8-0-0-139 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 373-5 Human Osteology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-140 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 374-3 Prehistory of South And East Asia, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-141 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 376-5 Quantitative Methods in Archaeology, 1985; F-4-8-0-0-142 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 385-3 Fossil Man, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-143 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 432-5 Advanced Physical Anthropology, 1985; F-4-8-0-0-144 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 433-5, 434-5, 435-2, 480-5 Field School, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-145 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 438-3 Geoarchaeology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-146 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 442 -5 Forensic Anthropology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-147 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 474-3 Regional Studies in Archaeology: Southwest North America, 1984; F-4-8-0-0-148 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 480-5 Directed Readings, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-149 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 485-5 Lithic Technology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-150 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 895-5 Directed Readings - Forensic Anthropology, 1984 - 1985; F-4-8-0-0-151 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 101-3 Prehistoric Past, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-152 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 131-3 Human Origins, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-153 (Archival box - standard 4-27)
  - ARC 200-3 Origins of Northern European Society, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-154 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 223-3 Prehistory of Canada, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-155 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 272-3 Archaeology of the Old World, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-156 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 273-3 Archaeology of the New World, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-157 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 301-3 Prehistory and Primitive Art, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-158 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 330-3 Prehistory of Latin America, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-159 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 332-3 Archeology and Resource Management, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-160 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 333-3 Primate Behavior, Spring; ARC 333-3 Archaeology of Britain, Fall, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-161 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 334-3 Special Topics: The Vikings, Shamans and Sorcerers, Archaeology of the Andes, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-162 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 335-5 Paleography of East and Southeast Asia, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-163 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 340-3 Introductory Zooarchaeology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-164 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 360-5 Indian Culture of North America, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-165 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 365-3 Ecological Archaeology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-166 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 370-3 West Pacific Prehistory, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-167 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 372-5 Archaeology Lab Techniques, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-168 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 373-3 Human Osteology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-169 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 376-5 Using Computers and Statistics in Archaeology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-170 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 385-5 Fossil Man, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-171 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 410-5 Advanced Archeometry, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-172 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 411-5 Archaeological Dating, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-173 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 432-5 Advanced Physical Anthropology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-174 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 433-5. 434-5, 435-2, 436-3 Field School: Techniques of Inquiry, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-175 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 471-5 Archaeological Theory, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-176 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 474-3 Archaeology of North America and Southwest, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-177 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 476-5 Regional Studies in Archeology: Pacific Northwest, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-178 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 480-5 Directed Readings, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-179 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 871-5 Graduate Theory in Archaeology, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-180 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
  - ARC 876-5 Selected Topics in Archaeological Method, 1986; F-4-8-0-0-181 (Archival box - standard 4-28)
- Archaeology field studies, 1966 - 1979; F-4-9; 16 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the Field School conducted by the Department in various locations. It includes correspondence, procedures, and field studies.
  - Field School Correspondence, 1966 - 1973; F-4-9-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field School Correspondence, 1974 - 1978; F-4-9-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field School Forms, 1970 - 1978; F-4-9-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - A Guide to Basic Field Procedures, 1973; F-4-9-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Bamfield), 1969; F-4-9-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Bella Coola), 1969; F-4-9-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Mayne Island), 1969; F-4-9-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Namu), 1978; F-4-9-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Pacific Rim National Park), 1972; F-4-9-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Railway Avenue), 1969; F-4-9-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 4-19)
  - Field Studies (Salvage Sites), 1971; F-4-9-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Field Studies (Salvage Sites) OFY students, 1971; F-4-9-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Field Studies (Salvage Sites) Management and phtographs, 1971; F-4-9-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Field Studies (Salvage Sites) Final report, 1971; F-4-9-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Field Studies (Wet Sites), 1978 - 1979; F-4-9-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
- Museum of Archaeology, 1967 - 1983; F-4-10; 12 cm of textual records
  The Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology officially opened on December 15, 1979. Series consists of records relating to the Museum. It includes correspondence, reports, and posters.
  Museum of Archaeology and Ethnology
  - Museum Correspondence, 1971 - 1975; F-4-10-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Museum Correspondence, 1976 - 1977; F-4-10-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Museum Correspondence, 1978; F-4-10-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 4-20)
  - Museum Correspondence, 1979; F-4-10-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Museum Correspondence, 1980 - 1981; F-4-10-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
    Restricted in part
  - Curator of Education, 1980 - 1983; F-4-10-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Museum Reports, 1973 - 1978; F-4-10-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Museum: Opening Ceremoney, 1979; F-4-10-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Museum Collections, 1967 - 1981; F-4-10-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Poster (oversize), [19--?]; F-4-10-0-0-10
- Publications, 1975 - 1986; F-4-11; 3 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to departmental publications, and includes the student newsletter Debitage and the Archaeological Student Society (A.S.S.) Anti-Calendar.
  Archaeological Student Society
  - Publications, 1976 - 1986; F-4-11-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Students Newsletter: Debitage, 1975 - 1977; F-4-11-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Student Society Anti-Calendar, 1975; F-4-11-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
- Associations, 1967 - 1981; F-4-12; 11 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to various professional associations, including the Archaeology Society of B.C., the Canadian Archaeological Association, the American Anthropological Association, and the International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. It includes correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, and reports.
  American Anthropological Association; Archaeological Society of British Columbia; Canadian Archaeological Association; International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences
  - American Anthropological Association, 1969 - 1977; F-4-12-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Archaeological Society of B.C., 1968 - 1981; F-4-12-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Canadian Archaeological Association, 1967 - 1973; F-4-12-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 4-21)
  - Canadian Archaeological Association, 1974 - 1976; F-4-12-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - Canadian Archaeological Association Conference, 1972; F-4-12-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - Canadian Archaeological Association Conference, 1973; F-4-12-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1975; F-4-12-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1976 - 1977; F-4-12-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, 1978; F-4-12-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
- Boards and conferences, 1975 - 1979; F-4-13; 17 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to various professional conferences and advisory boards, including the Provincial Heritage Advisory Board and the B.C. Heritage Advisory Board Permit Review committee. It includes conference programs, correspondence, memoranda, pamphlets, and reports.
  British Columbia Heritage Advisory Board
  - Symposium on Early Man in America, 1975; F-4-13-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - Conference on Northwest Coast, 1976; F-4-13-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - International Congress of Americanists, 1979; F-4-13-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 4-22)
  - Provincial Heritage Advisory Board 1st-4th, 1977 - 1978; F-4-13-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 4-23)
  - Provincial Heritage Advisory Board, 5th-9th, 1978 - 1979; F-4-13-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 4-23)
  - Provincial Heritage Advisory Board Correspondence, 1977 - 1978; F-4-13-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 4-23)
  - B.C. Heritage Advisory Board Permit Review Committee, 1978; F-4-13-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 4-23)
  - B.C. Heritage Advisory Board Permit Review Committee, 1978; F-4-13-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 4-23)
  - B.C. Heritage Advisory Board Permit Review Committee, 1978; F-4-13-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 4-23)